In this video, we'll talk about the product vision.
This topic is quite important for any product owner because they are the people who defined infrequently
communicate that vision.
A product owner is the chief product visionary.
He or she needs to make sure everyone understands the product vision.
Do you remember how the Springle guides the development team during the spring?
Well, the product vision is quite similar, but on a larger scale it guides the whole swim team towards
the end goal, the destination, the place we call success.
This program does not talk about product vision, but things from the talk.
You will find some resources on the topic.
So let's start from the very beginning.
What is the product vision?
Well, first of all, before we start with, the product development is product owners.
We need to answer the question.
It's a very important question.
Why?
What are we going to develop the product?
Let's keep it simple.
There is a problem in our product is the solution.
We cannot provide a good solution if we do not understand the problem on a deep level, and for that
reason I'm asking the question why helps us clarify revealed the real problems we are going to solve
with our product?
We should not be one of those people who jump straight on the solution and do not spend any time understanding
that the real problem.
So basically, the product vision is a short statement that is focused, clear and easy to understand.
It reflects the target audience and their needs.
It is emotional, I should say.
It can be emotional.
It is very persuasive.
It focuses on the outcome is if said, the destination we call success.
Now let's take a look at the vision of scrub the dog.
A world in which all software developers love their work and their customers love working with them,
as you can see, it is clear and focused.
The work love appears twice.
So, yes, it is emotional.
I find it very inspiring.
Obviously, that's a company vision and not a product vision, but still it gives us an idea.
Let's take a look at another example.
Spotify.
I love their product.
We envision a cultural platform where professional creators can break free of their medium's constraints
and where everyone can enjoy an immersive or artistic experience that enables us to empathize with each
other and to feel part of a greater whole.
It's not a very short but nice vision anyway.
He will not be given a vision statement when your example of people wanting to determine which one is
good and which one is bad.
What you need to understand, however, here is the concept.
Now, as a product owner, it is your responsibility to communicate the vision of the product, not
just not just with the Scrum team, this promising development, but also to the stakeholders.
And this is not something we do once at the beginning of the project of the product development, for
example, nor the product owner should communicate the vision frequently.
He or she can use this from events to do so.
For example, spring planning is a great opportunity to remind the team about the product vision, but
also a spring preview because key stakeholders participate in the meeting as well as you remember.
Also, you know, that's French retrospective is about the way we do things.
So it would be correct if we also discussed the way we communicate the product vision, for example,
besides talking about it sometimes before we have it written and place it somewhere that's visible in
the visible place.
Having a product vision also creates transparency.
Everyone on the team has a common understanding of why we are building the product and and of course,
the customer needs.
Having said that, the whole strong team, not just the product owner, has to have an idea and they
have to know how the product earns revenue and they have to know the needs of the end users.
OK, time to recap.
The product owner is the chief product visionary.
The first thing the product owner does when starting a new product is defining the product.
The protocol communicates the product vision often to the team and stakeholders.
This prevents, besides leaks from or great opportunities for the product owner to remind the team and
stakeholders about the product vision.
The product vision increases transparency and it gives some direction to all Sprint's.
The product vision is focused, clear, easy to understand, it reflects the target audience in their
needs, it can be emotional and persuasive.
OK, in the next video, we'll talk about another important topic value.
Thank you for watching and stay purposeful.