As I said in the previous lecture, the product owner captures high level ideas and puts them into product
backlog.
Nowadays, we use software like Djura.
This is one example, but many people still use sticky notes on a market.
That's OK.
It makes it very simple.
These sticky notes are the product backlog items, they are different in size, of course, and other
agile frameworks have names for the different sizes.
For example, the smallest item you can have is a task or you can also hear a subtask.
A bigger one is the story.
A bigger one is an epic and it's bigger than an epic is the theme.
Let's say you have an epic and you break it down into three user stories.
Then you break down these user stories into 13 tasks.
For example, a theme could be finalists epic.
One could be invoicing story one.
If we use user stories, of course, the format, it would be as a user, I want to be able to create
an invoice.
And then we have all the tasks related to creating an invoice design of the page at invoice bottom.
What fields will be there?
Agreed with all invoices, filters by date, filter filters, big companies, amounts, currencies and
much, much more.
But in scrum, we are not required to use these names.
What you have to know is that we are right, pbis, we refined him during the sprints, the development
embraced him down to tasks screwed up or calls that decomposing an item to a small unit of work.
For your exam, you have to remember a few key points here.
Scrambled egg is against having a definition of free, not only it's not mandatory to have a definition
of them, but also they are against it.
And I'll explain the moment.
On the other hand, a common characteristic of successful sometimes.
And, you know, we spoke in the previous lecture to have many items on top of the product backlog,
maybe four to Springsure, had maybe three sprints ahead.
But, you know, not that many items.
So it becomes waste.
And here it gets a little bit confusing because we do have a concept of freakiness.
We want the items on top of the product back to be ready for development.
That means.
First, they can fit into l'esprit, that's the first very basic requirement in second, they are clear.
We can also say they refined the development team understands them, but we do not have a definition
of rape.
Here is why.
When the product owner orders the items, he or she might put an item on the very top of the product
back.
Look, that item would bring a lot of value, but unfortunately it is not ready for development.
What should the developers do or do you think?
They should still selected for the sprint backlog and they will refine it during this during the sprint,
if we had an official definition of freedom that would force the developer to keep that item in the
next one in order know the next one is ready for development, for example, but it may not bring as
much fun is the first one that they skipped.
Now, this is the main reason and it goes back to how we order the product back.
Look, we do not order it based on the size of the items or based on radius.
You know precisely how we order it in a way that maximizes the value the product delivers.
So for your example, if you see a question in the lines of the items on top of the product, backlog
must be ready based on the definition of true or false.
You should pick forced, right, because the definition of radios does not exist in what exists is the
mindset, the concept.
Yes, we want the items on top to be ready.
We do our best for refinement, but that's all it is.
We are on the topic.
I want to remind you that on average, the items in the spring that look are smaller items on the top
of the product backlog in the items on the top of the product backlog are smaller than those on the
bottom.
This, again, we are talking on average here.
This is because we are decomposing the items.
We are making them clear.
Just think about breaking the items down.
If you see a question related to this related to sizes.
Now, let's recap product backlog readiness refers to the concept of items that are immediately actionable
or simply set ready for development, a definition of ready is not accepted.
Describe the product owners.
Try to have items on top of the product backlog if the permit backlog items on top of the product backlog
are not ready.
The developers have to pull them to the sprint backlog anyway.
In the next lecture, we will do a recap of the last four lectures.
After that, a quick quiz and then we will move to the definition of dumb.
Thank you for watching.
State Purposeful.