Let's talk about the definition of them.
What is it the definition of them is a formal description of the state of the environment when it meets
the quality measures required for the product.
The definition of then is not an artifact.
It is a commitment for an artifact.
This is the increment.
I've shared with you before, but I would like to think about the definition of an is a checklist.
These are all the points that the scrotum has to check off to say an item is done when an item is done.
It means normal work is spending.
It means that the item is usable by the end users, the moment a product backlog item meets the definition
of an increment is born.
This center says exactly the same because by default, an increment is tested and it is verified, it
is usable.
The definition of then is he must be strong and it increases transparency when we see this item is done.
All the members of the team know what that means.
If the organization, the Scrum team works and has a definition of done is part of is part of its standards,
then the team must follow it as a minimum.
If it is not an organizational standard, then the entire scrumping creates a definition of done that
is appropriate for the product.
Of course, yes, the product owner now the product owner in the scrum master have a say in the definition
of the product owner input will be related to quality from a business point of view of the schoolmasters.
Input would be related to quality improvements to the definition of done.
After all, Kronosaurus main accountability is the effectiveness of the scrum team.
And to be effective, they the scrum team must have a strong definition of the.
And when I said improvements to the definition of done, do you remember during which event we usually
discuss the definition of them?
I hope you've answered Sprint retrospective Gujjar.
The developers are required to conform to the definition of done when skills crunch.
We have multiples from kids.
Now, a quick reminder here.
When we have multiple scrum teams working on the same product, we have one for the backlog.
We have one product owner in one product goal at any given time.
We have multiples from my source and, of course, developers, but we also have one integrated increment.
In the scrum, we must mutually define and comply with the same definition of them for that integrated
increment.
Time for recap.
The definition of done is a formal description of the state of the increment when it meets the quality
measures required for the product, the definition of done is mandatory and it increases transparency
if the definition of done is part of organizational standards.
This company must follow it as a minimum.
If the definition of done is not part of organizational standards, this company must create one that
is appropriate for the product.
The definition of them may be improved during the project.
The result would be a higher quality of the work if multiples continue working on the same product they
mutually define and comply with the same definition of done for the integrated increment.
Thank you for watching.
I'll see you in the next video, state purposeful.