Let's talk about story points.
What are the story points are a relative unit of measurement.
The keyword here is relative.
For example, the team gets together and looks into a PBI.
Everyone has a good understanding of it and they estimate this item to be worth 10 story points.
If they need to estimate another item twice as big, that will be 20 story points or if the team can
get the thoughts, can do a third item in half the time in comparison to the first item, that would
be five story points.
Now, as I've said, we are interested in the relative value here.
The same example will be accurate.
If I said that the first item is 100 story points.
The second item is twice as big, 200 story points.
In the third item is 50 story points.
The roll numbers do not matter here.
When we estimate which story points, we always consider all the work that has to be done designing,
coding, testing, integrating and so on.
In other words, we take into consideration the definition of done.
If we have some special tests in the definition of them, we consider this well.
Well, estimating as well.
And to make my point, I would like to quote a man whose opinion I respect very much when we talk about
scrum and other agile principles, methodologies, frameworks and so on.
His name is Michael, and here's what he says.
Story points are a unit of measure for expressing an estimate of the overall effort that will be required
to fully implement a product backlog item or any other piece of work.
That's his definition of what story points are.
Mike talks about Deverall effort to fully implement a PBI.
As they've mentioned in earlier videos, we calculate the velocity of the team by combining the story
points, all of the items that were done in the past, during the past sprint or ideally an average
of the past several sprints.
This helps us determine how many PBIS the development team can handle during the next sprint.
And not only that, but we would be able to see how many sprints are left in the project.
Of course, if the PBIS are estimated, let me give you some examples to clarify.
Let's say that during spring one, the team managed to complete PBIS, which totals three points, twenty
five sprint to twenty two, three points, sprint three twenty seven, sprint for twenty and Sprint
five thirty one.
So if we calculate that we will get a total of one hundred and twenty five story points divided by five
sprints, we give an average velocity of twenty five.
Let's say that we have a product backlog with PBIS worth two hundred and fifty three points.
How many sprints do we need to finish the project.
Two hundred and fifty divided by twenty five equals ten sprints.
What's also good is that we know that our sprints are two weeks long.
That means we complete ten sprints for five months.
This information is quite important for customers and not only any types of stakeholders are interested
in that.
But please remember the velocity of the team changes.
It needs several sprints to get it stable.
The good news is that we can always recalculate with the new numbers.
Finally, what do we consider when estimating when to help us to points?
Of course, we start with the amount of work, but we also consider uncertainty, risk and complexity.
If you would like to dig deeper into these factors, I would recommend you read the blog post What Our
Story Points by Mike Cohen.
You would not need this information for your exam, but you would need it for your practice.
So I recommend you take a look in the next video.
I would like to introduce to you the Ploning poker.
Thank you for watching and stay purposeful.