OK, so we know what story points are now it's time to assign story points to the PBIS.
How do we do that?
One way is to use Ploning poker.
I'll be honest with you, in the company I work for, we do not use this technique.
We've never tried it.
But here is the concept.
Each member holds several cards with numbers on them.
A PVA is presented and each member gets to vote.
But here is the interesting part.
They pick up a card and hold it face down.
Then when everyone is ready, the cards are shown at once.
You might be thinking why?
Let me tell you, if the voting happens one person after another, the decisions will be influenced
by the first person who votes.
This is not good.
It's a cognitive bias called anchoring.
We use this frequently in marketing when we present prices.
Let me give you an example.
I will show the product and I'll tell you, this product costs 200 dollars.
I want to use that price to hundred dollars as an anchor, but then for a limited time only you can
buy that product for thirty dollars, which is a huge discount.
And in your mind, the deal you're getting is amazing.
This is the power of anchoring.
The same effect happens when we vote one after another.
Now imagine the most experienced developer votes, 20 story points for an item and everybody sees that
they will pick something very close to that number.
Some people would not even consider what they think their own opinion, because if this experience developer
thinks so, that must be the case, right?
No, this is not the result we want.
Everyone holds the cards face down and they are shown it was.
But what happens next?
We want to take a look at the highest number and the lowest number, for example, one person voted
20 story points.
Another person voted 100 sort points.
Well, what does this tell us?
That's a huge difference.
Maybe one of the developers does not precisely understand the task at hand or the other one is still
considering important points.
In any case, we do another discussion to clarify and then we would vote again after that.
So if the numbers are more or less in the same range, we take an average and go with it.
That's it.
We go to the next PBI in revoltingly.
OK, this was the planning pocho concept.
It's not mandatory scrum, but many scrum teams use it.
Thank you for watching and I'll see you in the next video.