Is a product warmer, it is your responsibility to measure the progress of the project.
You do this at least once per sprint.
You need to make sure the team delivers value after progress.
Measurement is mandatory.
But what is not mandatory are the diagrams or charts we would use to measure that progress.
Why is this lecture called Information Radiator's?
That is because the charts we use to measure progress radiate information.
You know, one of the pillars since is transparency.
We can draw and update the chart, put it in a visible place in everyone in the team knows where we
are, by the way.
Do you remember who measures the progress of the sprint?
It's the development team, they do that daily and they know best what's going on during the sprint,
very common charge competition, their fuels are burned down and burn up charts.
You might see questions from your exam about them.
So let's start with the burned down chart.
It's quite simple, by the way.
Here is how they look.
Here is how the burned out chart looks like.
The horizontal axis shows the time, the vertical axis shows the amount of work, so the burned down
chart shows how much work is left or said, in other words, the amount of remaining work across time.
The green dotted line is a trend line that shows our planet progress, but the blue line is our real
progress.
This is what actually happens.
As you can see, the more PBIS we complete, the more the blue line moves down.
You should know that the trend line is just an assumption when the project will be completed, if there
aren't any significant changes, or I should see no changes at all to the number of developers or the
scope of the project.
That's important because if you as a product owner constantly argue PBIS, basically you're changing
the scope of the project.
It would be impossible to end the project somewhere near the trend line.
Even those from international framework in energy, we don't do upfront planning.
Let's be realistic.
Sometimes the scrum teams will be working on a project with a deadline.
Now forget about the trend line for a moment and think of it as a deadline instead as a product where
you can draw this deadline yourself.
And what does it mean when the blue line is above the deadline?
It means we're behind schedule.
If we're under the red line, it means we are ahead of schedule.
Now the burned down chart can be used by the development team to measure the progress of this sprint.
The horizontal axis would show D and we can call it a spring burn down chart.
When the product owner uses such a chart, we can call it a project burn down chart.
Then the horizontal axis would natural names, but instead it would show Prince.
Besides, the burned down charred, a burned up chart also exists as a tool to track progress.
It shows the complete work and total work.
As you can see, the completed work start from zero and it goes up.
This chart shows any changes in the scope of the project.
The scope is the total amount of work, let's say we have a product backlog with temps estimated at
120 story points, that's our scope.
But the customer wants to add two more features.
More PBIS means more story points is a result.
The total amount of work increases.
And let's say that we've added to this worth 20 story points.
And the result is the blue line going up to 140 story points.
As you can see on the chart, if we remove PBIS, the burn up chart would reflect that as well.
The blue line would go down.
Now, some people would say it is better to use BORDENAVE charts instead of burned down because the
burned down chart doesn't show changes in the small bits.
That is not completely true because now instead of drawing it, you know, by hand, we have tools like
Jurez I've already mentioned.
And you can set it up in a way that the burned down chart would also show changes in the scope.
But this is not important.
As a product owner, it's up to you to choose how you will present showed the progress of the product.
And by the way, these are these are just two chart, but there are many more many more charts you can
use, for example, cumulative diagrams and in many other things.
But what is important here is your focus.
What do you focus on your measuring progress?
So that means everything should revolve around volume, not velocity and story points.
Yes, these charts are helpful, but the ultimate measure of success is the value your product delivers.
Let's do a quick recap.
Progress measure month is mandatory and strong, the economy measures the progress of the project once
first sprint to ensure value is being delivered, the burned out chart shows the remaining work across
time.
The trend line is simply a forecast and assumption when the project will end.
If there are no changes in scope and number of developers, the burn up chart shows the complete work
in total work.
Changes in the scope are clearly seen.
For your example, remember that chart of rooms are not mandatory.
Thank you for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.
We will talk about an interesting topic, the cone of uncertainty.
And remember, state purposeful.