You already know that the product owner is the value maximizer of the product.
And I believe this is one of the most important aspects to consider for this role in your.
One example, after all, is all about value driven development.
The keyword is value.
So let's talk about it.
First of all, you should know that there is financial value.
This is what for profit companies strive for, but there is also societal value.
This is what non-profit companies strive for, charities.
And so you need to remember this because you might see a question if success is only measured by financial
value, such as money, income or revenue.
And so.
The correct answer here would be false, because you can measure success by societal values as well.
It's not always about revenue and you know, that's from can be used for any type of product.
If we give it a deeper look.
What does it stay behind, fellow?
Happy inducers does the answer, everything revolves around fulfilling their needs.
This is why they pay to use the product.
So is a value maximizer.
You should be asking yourself.
What is the future that will bring the highest impact?
Well.
And to make that to make that decision to be decisive, you must understand the product in the market
of the product extremely well.
And if you do not have a business background, you don't know what the market is.
Let me explain simply.
The market is the people who have a need.
They want the product, but they can also afford it, so they have money to buy it.
You can also hear the term target audience.
That's OK as well.
So to know the market means knowing the end users to understand their needs.
Now, this does not mean that the product owner should do the legwork.
It can be someone else, for example, a marketing department or surveys.
But the data has to come to you as a product owner.
You have to it has to do that has to be analyzed by you.
And sometimes you might see differences between opinion, between the opinion of your customer, what
they want, and on the other hand, the end users and what the end users want.
What do you do in this case?
Which opinion is the heaviest?
What do you think?
It is the end users opinion be prepared for such a question on the exam so the people who pay to use
the product, the end users, are those whose wants and desires you must strive to satisfy.
First, of course, you do that in a civilized manner.
You have to wait.
You have to balance the opinions of all stakeholders.
So besides being decisive, the product owner should develop excellent communication skills.
Now, how do we deliver value?
There is only one way and this way is by making releases, you know that at the end of each sprint we
must have a potentially releasable increment.
But the releases might happen more frequently than that.
For example, in one sprint, you may have two or three releases or the opposite.
In two or three sprints, you may have just one release.
We can see a major release.
The point I'm making here is that we deliver value by releasing the increment.
And even though release planning is not an official storm event, it doesn't mean the product owner
doesn't do it.
OK?
There are many considerations.
That you have to make when you have to think about when you do release.
We will talk about more about that in the release when the release lecturer of the program.
But for now, let me give you just a few examples.
Can the customers absorb the product then your increment, or even if they can, can they absorb the
frequency maybe you're releasing too frequently?
The users need time to adapt.
Another consideration is that if if the product owner waits for too long, there's a risk that the value
of the increment the increment would deliver may get out of line with the marketplace in any case.
Once again, our product delivers value when it is released, if it is not released.
We are just working on it.
We don't have value.
We add only costs.
And this is why the waterfall model is not a good fit for software development.
If you're working between the company and you have stubborn managers that they cannot let go of the
waterfall model.
Instead of explaining everything you know about agile and scrum, you can ask them this question in
what timeframe?
When will our product deliver value to the end users?
What's that in eight months, in one year?
There is a chance many features wouldn't be used by the end users at all.
One reason is that the volume got out of line with the marketplace.
Remember, this is one of the considerations the product owner is making.
Another reason is unless you test your hypothesis with the marketplace, you cannot know if you are
right or wrong.
You've probably heard 45 percent of the features in the software product or never used in to waste the
wasting resources.
We are talking about here in comparison with Chrome and other agile methods and frameworks.
We deliver value each increment.
Possibly the release of the longest period to create the incrementing scrum is one month.
So in in one month we will have a potentially releasable increment.
Also, when we talk about value of its product owners, we should always consider the cost as well.
And here is why.
Let me ask you this.
Imagine you have developed three main features, the first one generates twenty three thousand dollars,
the second one generates fifty six thousand dollars, and the last one generates one hundred and eighty
thousand dollars.
Now.
Which feature delivered more financial value to the comic?
We cannot answer that question because we do not have enough information.
We cannot simply say the third feature because we do not know the cost.
What if feature number three cost us three hundred thousand dollars to develop in future, feature number
two cost us twelve thousand dollars to do?
This is why it's important to consider costs so you have a better understanding of the hour.
Why return on investment now?
For your example, PSP 01, here is what they expect from you.
When we talk about ordering the items in the product back.
Look, you order the items in a way that would increase the volume of the product or specifically based
on volume risk cost Independence's and quite positive.
You will see such a question or maybe more questions around that as well.
So, again, value cost risk, dependency, do not worry from now we will talk about that, a key.
Next, we can and should look at value with a more holistic approach and not just think about value.
The value we deliver outside the organization, meaning to the end users, but also inside the organization,
meaning to the employees and stakeholders.
We should know how to measure value and focus on four key value areas current value, unrealized value,
time to market and ability to innovate.
These are explained in the evidence based management guide.
We should read and understand is it will help us answer several questions on the exam, but we will
do that in the next lecture.
For now, let's do a recap.
Value can be financial and societal value is not only measured by income, revenue or money for non-profit
organizations, it may be increased safety or security, product ownership, excellent knowledge of
all the products in the marketplace.
If there is a difference in opinion between the end users and the customers, what you should consider
as most important is the end users opinion.
If they're happy, chances are everyone else will be happy to talk about other involved stakeholders.
Product owners deliver value by releasing the increment.
There is not a ruling strong that says how often we should release, we can release a few increments
at a time or we can also release a few times during the sprint.
The rule is each increment must be releasable.
The agile approach is better than the waterfall approach for software development because it delivers
value fast to the end users.
Waterfall delays followed by design product owners already the items in the product backlog in a way
that maximizes the value of the product.
According to the MBM Guide, there are four Kevo areas we should measure can improve current value,
unrealized value, time to market and ability to innovate.
Thank you for watching and stay purposeful.