I would like to present to you the cone of uncertainty, and the reason is you might not see a question
asking directly what the cone of uncertainty is, but you might see a question asking about the concept.
And if you know the concept, you would answer quickly and correctly.
So let's get to it.
The cone of uncertainty, what is it, what does it show?
Well, the key word here is uncertainty.
What the cone represents is the fact that at the very beginning of the project, the uncertainty is
the highest.
The more we do, the more we reduce uncertainty.
That's the whole deal here.
No need to complicate it, if you see questions about forecasts, just think about this.
The longer the forecast generally, the less accurate it will be, especially if you do a forecast at
the very beginning of the project where the uncertainty is the highest.
If you do it in the middle of the project, the forecast will be more accurate.
The horizontal axis shows the time.
The vertical axis shows how much we know about the project and the progression of iterations or sprints
for the shape of the call.
We gain more knowledge.
That's it.
Nothing complex here.
As you can see in the next video, we'll talk about technical debt.
Thank you for watching and stay purposeful.