Technical debt is a term that you miss you on your exam.
The concept is easy to understand.
It refers to the way the developers are planning in writing the code in software development.
You can create a feature in more than one way, meaning the desk can expedite the delivery of the future
and meet the deadline, for example.
Or they can take more time and write the code.
Let's say almost perfectly.
Usually stakeholders want features and releases fast.
But here is the problem.
The more we expedite the delivery of the features, usually the more technical debt we accrue.
Let me give you an example to illustrate.
Imagine the customer wants a simple page with a sign, the form with five fields'.
The development team can do that for him in two hours, or it can do it in eight hours, the same for
the same fields, it will work the same way.
Now, if the developers do it in two hours and the customer requests two more fields to be added later
down the line, the developers would need 10 hours to ask the two fields.
But if the developers did decide to form in eight hours, initially, they would need 20 minutes to
add the two fields.
In the first case, the developers accrued technical debt and it was paid later.
In the second case, the planning and the calls were of high quality and no technical debt was accrued.
Now, this is just an example I made of the numbers in the real world.
This might not be true, but it doesn't matter.
The example clearly illustrates the concept of technical debt.
Sometimes from teams intentionally incur technical debt, for example, they want to receive fast feedback
from the marketplace.
In other cases, the developers unintentionally incur technical debt.
Maybe the deaf who was working on the future was doing too much of our time is close to burnout.
And Pucci could not come up with the best solution code wise.
In any case, we'll need to reduce technical debt by doing what's called called refactoring.
Refactoring is rewriting a piece of code, the feature works the same way as with the old code.
We do not change the behavior of the future, but the performance or future updates now become way easier
and faster.
Refactoring, however, has its limits.
For example, if we are writing quality code, releasing many cool features, everyone is happy.
But we do not think about the architecture.
We don't think about scalability, we are short sighted.
And if we face some serious issues like security, where that scalability, data management and more,
we will find ourselves in a difficult situation.
In this case, even refactoring would not help.
What is there to refactor?
The code is already of high quality.
The technical debt we accrued here is of another nature, so technical.
That is not just one type, poorly written code.
No, there is more to that poor planning.
Refactoring is also related to the fact that we need resources to do it.
Let's put it simply, we need money.
The whole scrum team should be aware of this.
They should know the cost they will pay in the future to repay the debt.
And now when you know the concept, I think the sentence during a sprint quality goals do not decrease
would make more sense.
The quality of the work we do, our re expediting the delivery or are we taking the time to write code
of high quality?
Honestly, the topic of technical debt is quite broad, but I'm sure the information here is more than
enough for for your example.
Thank you for watching.
I hope this video has been helpful and I'll see you in the next one.