It's time to talk about releases, let's start with what we know about them.
The entire scrum team contributes to the release decision.
It's not just the product owner anymore.
All increments must be usable in the software world, we say releasable.
The commitment for the increment is the definition of each incremental moves the product closer to the
product goal.
This company may create multiple injuries during a sprint scrum.
Doesn't tell us when to release.
When we release an increment, we add value to the end users.
This results in societal or financial benefits for the organization, but also we receive feedback from
the end users.
So far, so good.
In a previous lecture, I have mentioned that we're not limited to just one release per sprint.
We can release a few a few times during the sprint if we want, or we can release a few increments at
a time.
The problem is that if we delayed the release, the volume might get out of line with the marketplace.
We will not receive fast feedback.
We won't make money also.
You do not receive validation from the marketplace.
What does that mean?
Well, it means that, yes, we ordered the items in the product backlog based on what we believe will
bring the most value.
But this is still on an assumption.
It has to be validated with the marketplace.
This is the only way to validate your ideas.
So is product owners.
If we wait for too long, we might build the wrong products, unfortunately.
Remember, a strong international framework, the core of 4G, LTE adaptation, having major releases
is typical for the waterfall approach.
Yes, it can happen in scrum too, but the whole idea is to be adaptive and the only way to test your
hypothesis is to put it against the marketplace.
In theory, it all sounds great and maybe easy.
What's the big deal?
Let's release of humpin.
But in reality, releasing can be complex because we have to consider many factors.
Let me give you an example.
Can the end users absorb the new release?
Maybe the organization has to provide training for the intruders.
What about if a new installation is required?
For example, will some end users be constrained in some way with the release?
Do the end users want the release at all and what are what are the reasons for that?
Maybe the last release we did was painful for them.
How can we make it better this there?
These are very important questions the product owners should ask themselves.
In other words, there is a cost associated with the major releases.
The cost of releasing the product owner should also focus on how to reduce that cost.
Of course, not all releases are equal.
Some are major, as I've said.
Others are minor.
For example, we can release a small increment to fix books, to fix existing books.
Or maybe there is a new regulation and we require to make some small changes, or maybe there is a new
feature and we want to we want to release it right away.
Why should we wait for a date in the future?
We can release it now.
It's ready.
It will provide felt.
We will get feedback.
Another important point I would like to mention is release preparation.
Not so much.
Other frameworks have special events where they prepare the increment for a release.
For example, a spring during which the development team has only refractory, only fixing bugs, doing
special tests and so on.
It's called a hardening sprint.
Well, the People for Safe Framework, the Safe Community Safe stands for Scaled Agile Framework might
criticize me here because they would say, Vladimír, a hardening sprint includes more activities.
But you must know that in scrum, special sprints do not exist, including a hardening sprint.
I know I've already mentioned that, but we're just getting deeper into the subject here.
All these activities, special tests, refactoring, fixing bugs, and so we do that during the sprits.
Another consideration is that if we have five sprints and all sprint number six, you have to do a lot
of tests before a release.
What does this tell us?
Well, it tells us that the previous sprints did not produce usable increments.
It tells us that the definition of done is weak.
That means the quality of the work the developers do is not as high as it could be.
We are breaking some rules and we do not want that.
Let's do a recap.
The Halstrom team contributes to release decisions, all increments must be verified in usable scrum,
doesn't tell us when to release.
It is not true that we can release only one sports print we're releasing.
We add value in receipt feedback from end users, which is the most valuable feedback we can get more
valuable than the customer who pays for the development of the product.
Also, we validate our assumptions.
This is validated learning.
We can have major releases and minor releases.
Major releases are typical for the waterfall approach to development, but we can also have major releases
in Scrum.
When we release, we should consider customer absorption constraints, values being delivered late to
the marketplace and the cost of the release.
There are no special sprinting programs such as Sprint zero or a hard sprint.
A rule of thumb, if you can release, do it.
In the next lecture, we will talk about Skillings Strong.
Thank you for watching and stay purposeful.