In this lecture, we'll talk about scaling strong.
As you know from the scrum, guys, the essence of scrum is a small team of people.
This is how it was initially designed.
However, scaling scrum has also become popular and there are frameworks created created around that.
For example, no one offered to buy from the dog is called Nexxus.
There is a Nexus Ghaffari probably you know it already, but there are also less safe and probably more
cases are you will see questions on your exam around scaley.
There are some rules that scrum that or believes in and they will test your understanding there.
This is because there are differences in the approaches in Skillings from Inscrutably doesn't agree
with.
So, for example, in some frameworks you can have multiple product toners for one product.
That's OK.
But according to come the term, this is not acceptable.
Now, let's take a look first.
And probably the most important thing is that for one product, you always have one product backlog,
one product goal in one product owner, regardless of how many teams are working on that product.
We spoke about that in 08.
And in the example in any images I prepared for you, we have three teams working on the same product.
As you can see, there is one product or one product backlog in the middle.
And we have multiple schoolmasters developers.
In this way, it's much easier and productive for one person to manage the product backlog, but there
is also a downside to it.
If too many teams are working on all the same product, the work for the product owner might become
too much.
He or she might be in a situation where they simply need help.
And if that's the case, the correct thing to do here is to delegate some of the responsibilities to
the development teams and not having multiple product owners or product or proxies or call them however
you want next.
Each team has its own sprint and we should know if we have to synchronize the sprint or what.
I'm talking about the length.
For example, we have three sprints, all of them two weeks.
What do we have to do that?
The answer is no, and many people will confuse here.
There is no such rule in.
This is how it would look like if we have three teams, the first one uses to be close friends and for
three months, that's the period they complete six points.
The second one uses one month long springs.
So they complete three sprints for three months, of course.
And the third one uses one week sprints in the complete well sprints for three months.
In this way, the teams are more flexible.
That's it.
Since each team has its own spring, that means they have their own spring backlog.
As you can see, the developer pulled the work from the same project back to their own sprint backblocks.
Next, the definition of done, do we have one or multiple?
I know you know the answer to this one, but here I will share just a few more details around that.
The answer is we can have multiple definitions of them, but there are some things we should know we're
looking at.
Let me be more specific.
These checklists are not completely different.
They have things in common and here is an example, on an organizational level, there is a definition
of done with five bullet points based on that definition.
That means create or craft one for the integrated increment.
That means they add more bullet points to the organization's definition of them.
So they end up with a definition of them for the integrated in increment with 10 bullet points, for
example.
Then each team can add more points and have its own definition of so one can end up with 12 bullet points.
Team two can end up with 13 bullet points in Team three with 11.
But here is the important part.
The definitions of done on a team level must be compatible with one another.
In this way, the teams can combine their work, the outputs of each sprint into one integrated increment.
I want to briefly talk about the scrum of scrubs in the scrum of scrums meeting, there is one participant
from each team.
We can think of those people as representatives.
You know, that's in the normal daily scrum we have.
What do we do?
We it's about Ploning, the work for the next 24 hours, but also very important.
It's also about synchronization of the developers.
Well, scrum of scrums is similar, but the synchrony, the synchronization here happens on teams level,
OK, it's not within the team, but all teams synchronized together usually.
What do they talk about?
Usually the participants discuss cross team dependencies.
They share information, they talk about integration and more.
OK, let's recap.
One product has one product backlog, one product owner and one product goal.
At any given time, there can be one or multiple schoolmasters.
The reason is that the scrum master can work part time and act as such.
For more than one team, the length of the sprints does not have to be synchronized.
There can be multiple definitions of them as long as they're compatible.
The teams must be able to combine the outputs of their sprints into one integrated increment.
This video is great to help you pass the PSM one popular one exams, but for your work, if you have
to apply skills, then I highly recommend you.
You just pick one of the frameworks for savings from it and study it.
I let me repeat again next to save less and more.
Thank you for watching and stay purposeful.