In this lecture, we will talk about contracts and budgets.
First of all, there are different types of contracts, but I want to present to that are the most widely
used.
Of course, every organization has its own budgeting process, but its product owners, we should know
how budgeting works.
We want a positive airway, we should do budget revisions once for Sprint, we should be able to explain
to the stakeholders where the money goes.
The first type of contract is a fixed price and a second is time and material.
Yes, you might see variations of these, but generally here is how it works.
With fixed price, the customer knows how much it would cost to develop the software product.
OK, that's good.
But if you have to make an offer to the customer, how would you calculate that fixed price?
Well, you need a detailed plan.
You need to know exactly the scope of the project.
That means a lot of upfront planning.
And was the problem with that?
Well, to start with, you know that this is not how agile works.
We're building the product incrementally.
We rely on feedback to adapt.
This is how we built the right product, not just any product.
So a fixed price contract is typical for the waterfall model is not fragile.
But is it is it still possible to have a fixed price contract and use the scrum framework?
Of course, any other ideal, a framework that exists?
And the answer is yes.
Sometimes as property owners, we do have a say in the budgeting process.
Sometimes we don't.
Nobody asks us and other times we ask for a fixed budget.
What do we do when we are asked to to to to say how much it would cost?
Some experts suggest that we at a price before we inflate the price, so to speak, because we know
that there will be a change of scope.
We know that the customer may request features more features after the releases and so on.
For example, in the book that I've been often citing here, the professional product owner author suggests
that.
We increase the cost of the spring by an extra member or two for development.
This is for risk mitigation.
And once we know the cost of the sprint and the potential velocity of the development team, we can
determine the number of sprints, for example, minutes.
Let's say, for instance, each one costs 100000 dollars.
That equals one million dollars for the product or for the project.
Another important point in the calculation here is that after the final release, there is a maintenance
period.
We don't know how long, but we should know about it.
We should have an idea and we should include that in the cost, even though we can have a fixed price
contract and be agile in the same way.
To some extent, yes.
You see that fixed price and scope limit agility.
Now, the other type of contract is time and material, basically we get paid by the time we spent developing
the product.
The good news here is that we do not need to the formula in the scope is not fixed.
We discovered the scope of the product by building and releasing increments, listening to feedback
from the marketplace.
In other words, this contract type is best for strong time and material types of contracts.
They are also flexible in the sense that the customer may increase or decrease the budget as we go,
as they see the value being delivered, as they see the return on investment.
As you can see, when we have a fixed price contract, most of the risk is on the organization that
develops the product.
But when we have a time in material type of context, most of the risk is on the customer and it's more
a more balanced approach in terms of risk is called kept time in material that.
Now the organization gets paid, but the time spent developing the product, as with the normal time
and material contract type.
But here we have a cap and that cap limits the total amount of spent.
So the customer never pays more than the cap, even if the development continues.
You will not see types of contracts on your exam, but I believe it's important to know at least the
basics here.
Lest we get.
The product owner revises the budget at least once, faceprint to make sure value is being delivered.
Generally, that's the end of the.
A fixed price contract type with fixed scope means that upfront planning is required, which is against
the original beliefs.
Fixed price contracts limit agility, but it is still possible to execute product development.
The timing material contract type is grateful, strong and agile in general.
Thank you for watching and stay purposeful.