For your exam, besides reading and understanding this cronkhite, you must do the same for the evidence
based management guide.
Fortunately, it is short just 11 pages, but there will be a few or several questions on the examination.
And of course, you need to be prepared.
The purpose of this lecture is to point your attention to the most important areas in the guide.
So let's read.
Evidence based management guide how to continuously improve business results when measuring business
value and using empirical management.
Overview organizations adopting agile product delivery practices can easily lose sight of their real
goal of improving the value they deliver by focusing on improving activities and outputs instead of
business outcomes.
Agile is a means to an end, not the end itself.
The whole point of adopting agile practices is to improve business performance.
When organizations lose sight of this, managers ask questions that seem sensible but might create unintended
and undesirable consequences.
Some examples of such questions are.
Is built automation present, are code standards or conventions being met?
What is the quality level of code artist first practices being used?
EU velocity increasing.
Our developers integrating the code frequently.
How frequently?
And I want to stop right here and make a few comments now.
For many people, these are just questions in bubbles, but there is much more than that.
For example, is team velocity increasing?
Well, this question derives from the fact that there are people who think or believe that velocity
is a measure of success.
And what was velocity, by the way?
Will you know that the development team is responsible for estimating the size of the PBIS?
A good practice is to use three points.
Three points are not mandatory, but do not worry about that for now.
Alisher, everything you need to know about scoring points in velocity, velocity, calculation in the
future.
Lecture for now.
Imagine for once the development team completes five PBIS each, PBI estimated with five story points.
So in total we have twenty five story points.
This is the development team's velocity during the next sprint.
If we complete PBIS worth thirty story points, we can say that the team's velocity increased by five
story points.
Great.
But does that mean we have delivered more value?
No, he does not mean that we simply do not know the correct answer here, would we?
It depends.
Can we use velocity as a measure of success?
No, we cannot velocity's about the speed at which the development team completes PBIS, but it does
not tell us if these PBIS will maximize the value of the product.
Be prepared for such a question on your exell.
Next, are developers integrating the calls frequently?
This is about the fact that code integration happens frequently during the sprint.
Why?
Because when the developers write a piece of called, you need to integrate it to the rest of the code
to see if it will work or not.
So when that's court integration, Heppell if happens frequently during the spring.
This is there is not an official event.
This is not an official event.
You know, code integration scrum doesn't tell us when to integrate the code.
We use the agile concept of continuous integration.
We'll talk more about that as well.
Next hour, test first practice is being used.
This one is good, I like it.
It refers to a practice called Test Driven Development, or TDD.
Yes, it's a good practice.
It does increase the quality of the.
But it's not mandatory strong.
By the way, TDD comes from extreme programming, which is one of the first, if not the first agile
framework.
In contrast to Scrum in XP, you will find many practices, for example, test driven development,
as I've said, pair programming, very, very famous collective called ownership.
It's more like a rule also refactoring.
And so all these are not mandatory in Akron, but often use.
As you understand by now, this has become more abstract and flexible in the same time, obviously,
the creators want to make it easy for companies to implement.
So test driven development programming, refactoring, great practices, widely used, but again, not
mandatory scrum developers may choose something else, and that is OK with crime.
Well, I do not think there is any substitute for concrete factory, but we will talk about that a bit
later.
The next question is built automation, president, quality of cold, cold standards.
These questions are not wrong, but they're not the most important ones where you talk about measuring
value.
And if you think.
But, Vladimír, quality of the cold, this relates to value.
If the court is right and well, free of bugs and users would be happy.
And here's my answer.
Yes, you have a point, but.
If the features that were used in this case, it will deliver zero value.
Next, while the answers to these questions are interesting, they do not help an organization improve
the value it delivers or its ability to deliver value monitoring, only that their use of practices
does not provide the best evidence of their effectiveness.
For example, tracking a development whose velocity says nothing about whether the team is actually
delivering something that is useful to customers or users without measuring value.
The success of any agile initiative is based on nothing more than intuition and assumption.
In contrast, the evidence based management EBM approach measures value delivered is evidence of organizational
agility and provides ways to measure and improve the ability to deliver value.
This approach enables organizations to make rational, fact based decisions, elevating conversations
from preferences in opinions to empirical evidence, logic and insight.
OK, let's recap now and we will continue with this guide in the next lecture.
Velocity is not a measure of success called integration happens frequently during the sprint test driven
development pair programming and user stories are good.
Practice is often used, but they are not mandatory in Skrull EBM approach measures.
Value delivered is evidence of organizational agility in provides ways to measure and improve the ability
to deliver value.
Thank you for watching in state.
Purposeful.