OK, let's continue with evidence based management, part two, IBM is an empirical approach that provides
organizations with the ability to measure the quality delivered to customers in the means by which they
deliver that value and to use those measures to get improvements in both.
And now here is the important part, figure one EBM consists of four key areas unrealized value, current
value, ability to innovate in time to market.
OK, so listen, before Kvas give Schiavelli areas, you need to understand them as you will see questions
on your pure one exam, as they've already said.
For example, I'm certain I saw a question about time to market.
The good thing here is that these Kevo areas are super easy to understand.
Take a look at what the guide says.
Each KVA focuses on a different aspect of eider of value or the ability of the organization to deliver
value organizations without strength.
In all, four, Kiva's may deliver short term value, but will not be able to sustain it, delivering
value, happy stakeholders and satisfied employees.
Current values are important, but organizations must also show that they can meet market demand with
timely delivery time to market while being able to sustain innovation over time.
Ability to innovate continued investment in the product is justified based on measures of its yet unrealized
value that could be realized if the product possesses the right capabilities.
Now, let's briefly touch on each Cavaleri current value, as the name suggests, this area is above
the value the product delivers.
Now, as you can see, the guide gives us example questions to help us reevaluate the current value
area.
How happy are users in customers today?
Is their happiness improving or declining?
How happy are your employees?
How happy are your investors and other stakeholders?
Is their happiness improving or declining?
Do you notice the keyword here?
Happiness.
But this is not new to you because we spoke about it in the electoral vote.
Now, each KVOA is associated with several key value measures at the end of the guide.
You'll see that K.V. Ms.
Eveillard measures explained.
It's not necessary for you to learn in my heart, but read them a few times and understand them.
These cavey Ms.
Show us what to measure and what to strive to improve by using learning looks.
But more about that a bit later.
The CVS for the current value area are revenue per employee product, cost ratio, employee satisfaction,
customer satisfaction and customer usage index.
Next time the market well, this KVOA has to do with speed, how quickly do we deliver value?
Do you remember one of the considerations of the product on the Web planning releases was he or she
must be careful not to miss the window that the increment would deliver value, because if the product
on wait for too long, the value the incremental would deliver might get out of line with the marketplace.
The curves here are built in integration, frequency release, frequency release, stabilization period.
Meantime, to repair cycle time and lead time.
Next ability to innovate.
This one is about the ability to deliver new capabilities and innovative solutions.
Now, I want to point your attention to this, a variety of things, Skinny Pete, a teen from being
able to deliver new capabilities and, well, spending too much time fixing defects or reducing technical
debt, having to maintain multiple code and so on and so on now.
I have a dedicated lecture on technical debt because it's a product you should be aware of these concepts,
but the sentence I've just read should be a reminder to us that the purpose of this print is to create
a potentially releasable increment that delivers value.
Scrum does not allow special spreads, for example, sprint for removing technical debt or a sprint
for removing bugs.
Technical Sprint's hardening sprint sprint zero do not exist in school.
And I'm certain you will see questions on your example about the CVS for the ability to innovate are.
Feature usage index.
Innovation rate defect trends on property index is fulled versus index technical debt production incident
trends, active court branches, time spent merging called between branches in time spent context switching.
Next, unrealized value.
This one is about the value that the organization could realize in the future, the product owner should
be aware if the unrealized value is high or low, if it is high, that means that there is great market
potential.
If it is low, it means that we are reaching the end of the product lifecycle.
There are only two key measures for the unrealized value area.
The first one is market share and this is the relative percentage of the market controlled by the product.
In the second one is customer or user satisfaction.
Yep, this is the difference between a customer or user desired experience in their current experience.
OK, now let's talk about the learning new.
How to improve empirically using evidence based management, step one, quantify how we quantify the
value in the form of KVI.
Ms.
Stepto measure caves, we establish a baseline, a starting point that we will compare to later step
three, Celenk Kvas Kevo areas to improve here we are advised to improve the Kvas one or few at a time.
Take them for Conduct's practice experiments to improve Kiva's step number five evaluate results.
Now, as you can see, I went over the learning so quickly on the popular one exam, I did not see questions
related to, for example, you're not expected to know the steps of the learning law, but you are expected
to know the key value areas in some of the key measures.
You're expected to know that the end goal is not to be agile.
The end goal is to deliver value.
Agile is, the guide says, is just a means to an end.
The end goal is not to implement a practice such as test driven development TDD or using story points
or user force or planning or you name it.
The main goal is to deliver value both internally.
To the team and stakeholders and externally to the end users.
A quick recap.
According to the event, guys, there are four key areas, current value, time to market, ability
to innovate, unrealized value.
Each Kevo area kaffiyeh is associated with the volume measures, cavey amps improving performance is
an iterative process.
It uses a learning loop.
We measure the current state, we set performance goals.
We do small experiments, and then we measure the results to gauge the effect.
Then we do that again and again and again continuously.
By now, we have an understanding of what success means, delivering value on time, happy customers,
teams and stakeholders in the next election.
We'll do a recap of the last four lectures and then we will do a quick quiz.
And after that, we'll talk about some wrong measures of success.
Thank you for watching and stay purposeful.