I want to start this lecture with the fourth sentence from the Agile Manifesto responding to change
over falling a plan, as you remember, from a previous lecture.
We do planning in our job, but what we don't do is be detailed, upfront plans for the whole project.
We want to be agile.
We want to be adaptive.
Instead of following a big plan, we won't allow the customer and the end user to provide us with feedback
and based on it, we develop accordingly.
With that being said, if you see questions related to measuring success, we schedule budget in scope.
And I want to underline the word scope here.
You should know that these are not measures of success.
Scrambled egg is very sensitive about the awards, product and project they believe in product management
and development, not project management.
You also know that in strong we do not have a project manager role, but in traditional project management,
we do have project managers, of course.
And what do these project managers do?
Very briefly, they gather information and create an initial plan with a scope, of course, time and
budget.
They ask for resources, they assign tasks.
Reporting is a big deal.
By the way.
Sometimes developers have to explain what they've been working on hour by hour, Gantt charts are being
used and so on.
Having said that, do not understand that project management is something that or it does not work.
Nor the problem comes when managers use it incorrectly.
Here is what I mean.
Most of the time, project managers measure success by adhering sticking to the initial plan as close
as possible.
The project has met the deadline.
It has to be on budget or under budget, within scope.
It all sounds good.
It sounds logical.
But in the book, The Professional Product, the authors are asking, but what about projects that remain
on time, on budget and within scope and yet still do not succeed?
And they give us an example with Nokia, they produced mobile phones with a high success rate in terms
of their project.
Nokia was the leader in the mobile phone industry, the mobile phone market.
They followed very tight schedules to produce the phones, but they ended up as a Department of Microsoft.
Nokia didn't make the mental shift from project thinking to product thinking.
Again, it's about delivering value through products and not about delivering projects on time, budget
and within scope, simply simply because you can be on time, within budget, in the scope, but still
do not deliver value.
And I read something interesting, something funny on this topic.
It was a blog postings from the talk.
The operation succeeded as the project, but the patient died.
That's the product.
This is the result when project management is used incorrectly, when the focus is on the wrong place.
It is not on the end user.
And there needs.
And now the question is product owners who practice product development, what should we focus on?
Consider the Foley building the right product, focusing on meeting customers needs and happiness,
creating a product vision.
Balance in priority or risk value opportunities independence's to help you build the product in the
right way in the right order, maximizing revenue and ROIC, return on investment, measuring success
with business metrics like user adoption and retention in revenue or cost savings generated per feature,
frequently releasing product increments to obtain earlier feedback from the marketplace.
By using the product mindset and approach, we eliminate waste because we do less task management,
we do less people management as opposed to the project mindset instrument, you know that we have self
organizing teams.
Nobody pushes back to the development in the pool.
The items from the product backlog, they decompose the items into smaller units we call tasks.
And then the developers, they assign the tasks to themselves that fosters creativity.
It's the supporting system instead of a task pushing system.
OK, time to recap.
Responding to change over following a plan.
Time, budget and scope are not the best measurements for success.
Yes, these metrics can be useful.
They are useful.
But this is not how you measure success in school successes.
Crumb is delivering value for products.
So we have happy end users, scrum teams and stakeholders.
Useful business metrics for the product owner are user adoption and retention.
We want to grow our customers and our customer base, but we also want to keep the customers we already
have.
Revenue or cost savings generated by our future.
We strive for higher revenue and lower costs for the organization in strong corporate management activities
are distributed among all members of the scrumpy.
We do not have an equivalent of a project manager.
In the next lecture, we will talk about the product back, look into attributes of the items in it.
Thank you for watching and stay purposeful.