As a product owner, you are responsible for creating and ordering of the product back, look, you
order the product backlog items to maximize the value of the product delivers.
This is considered product backlog refinement in this video.
I want to focus on the product backlog items PBIS in their attributes.
But first, as a product owner, where do you get ideas for the PBS, for those PBIS, there are a few
sources.
The first one is the customer, of course.
Second, there might be representatives of the end users.
You get ideas from them as well.
Other people will emerge.
And certainly really, for example, the development team can write them.
You already know that this is OK.
The product owner can delegate that activity.
But while gathering requirements, you don't repeat what the customer says and write.
It is a product backlog item in the product that no, you need to analyze the information.
You need to ask why.
What problem does that future solve, because many times you and the development team, you will be
able to come up with a better solution to a specific problem than the solution proposed by the customer.
And given the fact that there's a product on how you engage with stakeholders, customers included,
you can propose a solution, explain the benefits of doing it that way and move on.
Most of the time you would notice that the customer will be OK with that.
Now let's zoom in the product battle items.
If you remember, we said that one characteristic is that the product items are non-technical.
The product owner and the stakeholders can discuss them easily, either PBIS or technical.
That would create a barrier and the customer wouldn't be able to understand exactly what we've done
during the sprint.
And this may be a problem with providing us with feedback.
Can we?
We do not we do not want that to happen.
So we really strive to keep the PBX.
Remember, when the developers break down the PBIS into tasks, these tasks, these tasks become technical.
After all, the developers will be writing code.
They would talk about installing an external database if you see assess scripting languages.
And so another characteristic is that we try to keep the items independent of each other.
And the whole purpose here is that if there are too many dependencies, the product owner would have
a hard time ordering the product backlog so that we can morph CBIS to eliminate the dependencies.
Sometimes we cannot do that, but we always strive to have independent items.
These two characteristics, non-technical and independent PBIS, come from another ARGEL framework called
Extreme Programming, or EXPE.
You should know that these two characteristics are not mandatory instrument, but is a product owner.
You should know them and you should try to apply them to your work.
Next, I want to talk about the attributes of the PBS first description.
Scrum does not have a template that we can use.
They do not restrict us on how to write the description of the PBIS, but the most common way is to
use user stories.
And here is a template as a user type.
I want to go so that.
Reesa, let me give you an example.
As a user, I want to be able to schedule an appointment and be notified one day.
Universal.
I do not forget as an administrator, I want to be able to insert text in video testimonials from happy
customers or my testimonials page.
By the way, I give you more user for examples a bit later, but that's the whole idea.
This is the most common way to write a non-technical description.
The next attribute size in the past, it was called estimation that since the stronger it is less prescriptive,
the word size appeals to more industries in the word estimation refers more to the IT industry.
Again, Scrum doesn't tell us how to size the PBIS or what unit of measurement to use, for example,
story points or Menelaus guilty.
And so in a few videos, I'll provide you with more details from three points.
But for now, I want to ask you, do you remember estimates of the size of the PBIS?
Who does the size of the PBIS?
I'll be happy if you've answered the developers.
The developers who will be doing the work are responsible for the sizing.
Moreover, they choose how many fish to pull from the product back, look to the spring back.
Look, if they've estimated they can do three pbis this print, the perfect plan doesn't push them and
says, no, no, no, that's not enough.
Let's put two more pubis in the street.
This is against this current rules.
And a quick reminder, we do not have a development team anymore.
We have members of this committee or code developers, those also the people who create a usable increment.
Next, we have author of the PBS is, you know, by now the product owner orders the items in the product
backlog in a way that maximizes the value the product delivers, but they also consider cost risk and
dependencies.
These are the three attributes Cronkite provides.
But it is important to remember that depending on the domain of work, these attributes might be different.
I've already gave you an example with the words size and estimation in the past, there was a fourth
attribute value.
We do not have any more, but I would like to share something with you about it because I believe it
will be useful to practice.
First, some strong teams use value points to estimate the value the people will deliver.
This concept is similar to the story points in the old days of Scrum.
This is how we order the items, the product backlog, the backlog item with the most other points.
These items go on top of the product backlog.
But the problem here is that we look at the product backlog items and their value individually and not
as a whole.
PBI number one, 300000 points, PBI number two to two hundred and fifty valid points.
Number three, one hundred and fifty valid points.
That's the order.
The second and current approach is to order the items in a way that maximizes the value of the product.
And I hope I do not confuse you here, but there is a difference in the approaches.
For example, I can have a small task, PBI that, when released, would generate a lot of value because
it enhances an existing feature and existing functionality.
In this case, I'm looking at the whole.
But if I look at that PBI separately myself, well, it's not that big of a deal.
It would not be that valuable.
Maybe I would put 50 valid points and it would be somewhere lower in the lower position in the product
backlog.
Lastly, what items can you put in the product backlog?
The regular feature is this is a normal thing to do.
You will try to make user stories, for example.
But what about no functional features or requirements?
These have to do with the way other features work, examples of non-functional features will be security,
performance, speed, reliability, maintainability, and what is a learn in the lecture about the definition
of then it's a good idea to put such requirements in the checklist in the definition of the checklist,
because these are not functional features.
They apply to all other features.
They apply to the way all other features work.
But for your example, you should know that you can put such items in the product backlog as well.
Time to recap.
The three main attributes of the piece are description, size and order.
In the past, we had value is a Ford attribute, but it has been removed from the strongest attributes,
often very with the domain of work.
The PBI should be non-technical and independent.
This is not mandatory in school, but it's good for your practice.
A common way to write the description of EPB is to use user stories not mandatory in scrum.
A common way to estimate the size of a PBI is to use story points not mandatory in scrum.
A common way to estimate the value of a PBI is to use value points again, not mandatory.
In Scrum, the product owner orders the items in a way that maximizes the value of the product in more
specifically value, cost, risk and dependencies.
Non-functional features can be added to the product backlog and the definition of dumb.
Before we go to the next lecture, you might ask Vladimir most of the things you've shared with us in
this lecture are non mandatory strong.
Why should we bother?
Obviously, there is more than one way to do things.
For example, estimate you can use three points, you can use man hours and so on.
And I want to address this.
I want to answer this question.
The reason is that you will see these practices and activities in your example.
And when you know them, when you know something is not mandatory or something is mandatory, this would
help you answer correctly and it will save you time.
For example, you see the product almost right, user stories and so on.
Yes, I read the question from beginning to end, but you know that the product owner must not he or
she is not required to use user stories.
These are the things that will get you to a really high score on your exam.
Thank you for watching and stay purposeful.