One of the focus areas on the spill, one example is product backlog management or refinement.
By the way, in the past it was called product backlog, product backlog grooming.
But the worst grooming has negative meanings in some countries, and that's the reason why it was changed
to a refinement.
In the video about the product owner, I've mentioned and explained what product backlog refinement
is, the purpose of this lecture is to broaden your understanding of the topic so you can confidently
answer questions related to it on your exam.
First of all, let's see what this guy says.
Product backlog items that can be done by the within one sprint are deemed ready for selection in a
Sprint planning event, they usually acquire this degree of transparency after refining activities for
the backlog.
Refinement is the act of breaking down and further defining product backlog items into smaller, more
precise items.
This is an ongoing activity to add details such as a description, order and size attributes, often
very with the domain of work.
The developers who will be doing the work are responsible for deciding the product.
Owner may influence the developers by helping them understand in select trade offs.
This middle passage says a lot of things, but let's take a look at that example.
First of all, you know that we have a scrum event that is designed to collect feedback.
Do you remember which one of those?
I hope you've answered Sprint Review, but in reality, we can receive feedback at any time you are
the product owner and the customer comes up with a great idea.
He or she comes to your office because they want to share the idea in person.
It is in the middle of the sprint.
And in fact, you like the idea.
You assume that it would bring a lot of value as well.
What do you do next?
You write a product backlog, I tell.
And this is where the developers step in, why?
First you explain the idea to them and they would say if there are any technical limitations or dependencies,
and second, they would estimate the size of the item.
In this way, the product owner would have an idea of how much time and effort would go into the development
of that item.
And based on that, the product owner would decide the order of the item if it is quick and easy to
do.
But it would bring a lot of value.
The product owner would put it on top of the product backlog if the same item would bring again a lot
of value, but it takes a lot of time to do, then the product owner would not be willing to put it
on top.
They would put it in a lower position.
My point is that we receive feedback spontaneously.
This is why product backlog refinement is an ongoing process is, you know, by now we don't have a
rule anymore as to how much time the developer should spend doing product backlog refinement.
Also, the product owner spends as much time as needed refining the product backlog.
Sometimes product owners can do product backlog refinement by themselves, they do not need the developers
all the time when refining, for example, there are 10 independent PBIS, all of them estimated in
the product owner wants to reorder them.
That's fine.
He or she goes ahead and does it or maybe some of the PBS are not relevant anymore.
No problem.
The product owner goes ahead and removes them.
But what is absolutely necessary for you to know for your exam is that the product owner does not estimate
the size of the items in the product.
Owner does not tell the developers how many items to pull from the product backlog to the spring backlog.
But another rule is this the developers must choose all the items from the very top of the product that
look downwards.
It is not acceptable for the developers to go ahead and pick items from the middle of the product backlog.
Of course, all things being equal here, the items on top are refined and ready for development.
I know I'm repeating myself, but these are the details that that you will see in the questions on the
one exam, because when you know the rules, it's easy.
Imagine you read following the product owner estimated the size of the PBA to be.
That's it.
You already know that this is not correct.
And whatever scenarios and to give you after that, they give you the question, no problem.
They cannot confuse, you know, the rules.
The next time I remember, it was a similar situation, but it was about the product owner changing
the definition of them without consulting with the developers.
Not acceptable.
We will talk about that soon.
Now, an effective scrum team is one that does product backlog refinement in the result is PBIS for
approximately two sprints ahead in the product backlog that are ready to be selected for development.
Let's say the developers do 10 PBIS first print.
Well, that means approximately 20 PBIS.
The first 20 PBI should be refined.
This is a characteristic of high performing scrum teams, but it is not a rule.
Refind means the developers understand them well enough to start working on them immediately.
Now, a question for you, let's say you have a product backlog with 150 PBIS if product backlog refinement.
Is that good?
Should you as a product owner, of course, together with the developers, go ahead and refine all 150
items?
What do you think?
The answer is no, you should not.
It's not a good idea why, because there will be a lot of items out of these 150 that the developers
will never do.
We consider this is waste.
We lost time, by the way.
I saw a question that revolves around that in the exam as well.
And finally, you've heard me a few times saying that items on top of the product backlog are ready
for development in here.
Another question appears, do we have a definition of readiness escrow?
We will answer this in the next lecture.
For now, let's recap from BackTalk.
Refinement is the act of adding details such as description order in size to the items in the product
backlog, product backlog.
Refinement is an ongoing process and ongoing activity.
There is no official event for it because we receive feedback spontaneously.
We want to do product batuque refinement on an ad hoc basis.
The product owner and developers collaborate during product backlog refinement.
Only the developers do the sizing of the PBS.
If this from must end, the product owner do not act as developers.
The product owner spent as much time as needed refining the product backlog.
Effective scrum teams keep the PBIS on top of their product backlogs refind.
That means the items are ready for development immediately actionable.
Thank you for watching, interstate purposeful.